Kelcey Wilson

Berkeley, California GitHub: https://github.com/kelceywilson

Full stack software engineer who is enthusiastic about building well-designed products and businesses that work the way they should. My broad experience includes production and logistical work that lends a practical wisdom to my approach.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Apprentice

2017-2018

Learners Guild Oakland, CA

During my Learners Guild apprenticeship, I created multiple full-stack applications built in Node/Express, using both PostgreSQL and MongoDB/Mongoose. For the front-end, I learned to prefer the ease and flexibility of my own CSS styling and the power of React-Redux combined with libraries like jQuery for bringing life to page. Finally, I use Git and Github to manage and deploy my projects to services like Heroku and Amazon Web Services.

Office & Community Logistics Manager 2014–2016

Yerdle, Inc. San Francisco, CA

Originally described as Office Manager, the work evolved into three main categories: Office management, logistics, and production management. In addition, it fell to me to do a variety of work that didn't fall neatly into another departments, including events planning, HR support (particularly new employee onboarding), executive support, transforming half of the office into temp office space and managing it, and countless other unforeseen tasks as they arose. I found myself essentially filling the role of Head of Operations without the title over this time and learned many new skills. Of particular relevance here was learning SQL, which I used to help produce dataclips for the Community Team and other purposes -- this is how I discovered my love of programming, and what lead me to my current path.

Logistics Specialist

2013 - 2014

Yerdle, Inc. San Francisco, CA

This was originally independent contractor job for a startup to set up and run a shipping system that would eventually be phased out. Eventually, the role evolved and I was given the office management job outlined above.

Office Manager/Volunteer Coordinator 2013–2014 Barbara Lee for Congress Oakland, CA

My main work at this campaign office was to ensure proper routing and resolution of communications (phone, mail, email) from internal and external sources (staff, constituents, supporters, etc.), logging and routing financial contributions, and assigning available volunteers to their best possible tasks. The role also regularly involved event preparation, public outreach, and tabling.

Pedicab Driver

2013 - 2014

Golden Gate Pedicab San Francisco, CA

Pedicab (tricycle taxi) operator in San Francisco.

Owner & Operator

2008 - 2012

Cappuccino Cottage San Diego, CA

I took over this small coffee shop that was losing about \$1000/month and with no previous business or restaurant experience, turned it into a profitable business in one year. I achieved this by instituting a variety of efficiencies, including setting up new point of sale, inventory tracking, and bookkeeping systems. During this time, I managed all aspects of retail coffee shop, including employees, payroll, inventory, budgeting, marketing, serving customers, light plumbing, electrical, etc.

Thesis Project

2006 - 2008

San Diego State University San Diego, CA

Explored federal political system by running as unaffiliated candidate for US President and running my own campaign. This involved learning and a number of new technological skills in addition to the intricate details of what it takes to run a campaign. The write-up itself took a year and over 200 pages, but a few lessons included: creating streaming web video channel to broadcast campaign to public in real time; creating a campaign website; writing press releases; participating in alive Internet audio debate; creating a campaign blog & regular posts; campaigning in 25 states; creatingpromotionalmaterials.

Proofreading Supervisor

2000 - 2003

Learning Tree International Los Angeles, CA

This was a new position created to manage a somewhat troubled proofreading team. During this time I transformed this department -- plagued with backlogs, excessive overtime, and conflict -- into a team that always met deadlines equitably without overtime or reduction in quality. The main role was to manage up to 6 proofreaders in the bimonthly production of 7 catalogs and a range of collateral. In order to address questions of productivity, I developed an individual and departmental productivity tracking system in Access with VBA. I also developed a Lotus Notes database to serve as an online proofreader style guide, term list, and forum. I was also responsible for writing yearly employee performance appraisals.

Production Editor

1998 - 2000

Business History Review, Harvard Business School Boston, MA

Bringing the production of Business History Review up to date helped me realize that I could transform businesses with efficiencies and hard work where others failed. I brought the quarterly scholarly journal, which was a full year behind schedule, up to date in two years. This meant proofreading, copyediting, single-handedly producing (in QuarkXPress, FrameMaker, and Photoshop), and coordinating printing of the journal while managing its routine business administration activities. This achievement also required regular correspondence with authors and referees, tracking the status of assignments, and maintaining status reports; upgrading and maintaining various databases (subscription, financial records, contacts, etc.); designing and placing advertisements, promotions, and direct mail campaigns. I also developed and maintained the journal's first web site.

Casual

1996 - 1998

Business History Review & Baker Library, Harvard Business School Boston, MA

This was a part-time support role I took while a full-time student in which I learned all I needed to take over the Production Editor role (outlined above) when it became available. The role involved copyediting articles and book reviews; corresponding with subscribers and agents; maintaining, organizing, and updating subscription databases, financial and copyright records; and transcribing, typing, editing, and proofreading articles and reviews submitted to BHR.

Production Coordinator

1994 - 1995

On The Ball El Monte, CA.

Originally hired to help with shipping, the role evolved into the first production coordinator for a rapidly growing toy manufacturing startup, and supervising the shipper in my former role. This meant establishing its production, inventory, and shipping systems. I was fortunate to discover the power of Excel -- using technology to make any role more efficient would become a theme in my career.

Radioman/Service Coordinator

1990 - 1994

NAVCOMTELSTA U.S. Navy, London, U.K.

Supervised all aspects of naval message center telecommunications service desk. Cleared for Top Secret access.

EDUCATION

San Diego State University, San Diego, CA - M.A. Liberal Arts & Sciences

2005-2011

Boston College, Chestnut Hill, MA - B.A. Philosophy, cum laude

1994-1997